<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>Autonomous Underwater Vehicle Challenge Blog</title>
        <link>https://blksail-edu.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>Autonomous Underwater Vehicle Challenge Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Welcome AUVC 2025!]]></title>
            <link>https://blksail-edu.github.io/blog/welcome-2025</link>
            <guid>https://blksail-edu.github.io/blog/welcome-2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Hello Trailblazers,]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello Trailblazers,</p>
<p>Welcome to the 2025 edition of the MIT Beaver Works Summer Institute – Autonomous Underwater Vehicle Challenge, powered by  <a href="https://www.blksail.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">blkSAIL</a> !</p>
<p>You're about to embark on a one-of-a-kind expedition into the thrilling world of underwater robotics. Over the next four weeks, you’ll not only learn to command autonomous submarines—you’ll become engineers, strategists, and innovators shaping the future of marine technology.</p>
<p>This isn't your typical classroom experience. You'll be diving deep (figuratively!) into Python, C++, physics, and autonomy, using your creativity and technical skills to control real underwater robots. You’ll be challenged to build, program, and fine-tune systems that can execute complex missions—just like what’s done in real-world marine exploration, defense, and environmental monitoring.</p>
<p>Expect early wins, late-night breakthroughs, unexpected bugs, and the pure thrill of solving tough problems with your teammates. You’ll be learning from industry professionals, researchers, and mentors who are just as excited as you are to explore the unknown.</p>
<p>You’ve earned your place here—and we’re thrilled to have you. Whether you come in as a robotics enthusiast, a curious coder, a mechanical tinkerer, or simply someone who thrives on a good challenge, this course is your space to grow. Over the next few weeks, you’ll sharpen your technical skills, expand your creativity, and discover just how far you can go when you combine teamwork with innovation. We're excited to see what you'll build, break, and boldly reimagine.</p>
<p>This is your launchpad. So take the plunge, get your hands dirty, make mistakes, fix them, ask questions, and most of all—have fun. The ocean of knowledge is vast, and you’ve just set sail.</p>
<p>Let’s make some waves!</p>
<p>See you in the pool,</p>
<p>Mohamed Saad Ibn Seddik, Dr.Eng.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>welcome</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Welcome AUVC 2023!]]></title>
            <link>https://blksail-edu.github.io/blog/hello-2023</link>
            <guid>https://blksail-edu.github.io/blog/hello-2023</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Hello Adventurers,]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hello Adventurers,</p>
<p>We are thrilled to welcome you to the BWSI AUVC 2023 by <a href="https://www.blksail.ai/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">blkSAIL</a> ! You're about to embark on an exciting journey into the world of underwater robotics, an adventure that will introduce you to cutting-edge technology, creative problem solving, and invaluable programming skills.</p>
<p>Over the next four weeks, you'll be diving (metaphorically, of course) into the fascinating realm of underwater robotics. Your curiosity, creativity, and coding skills will be your tools as you learn to program and control off-the-shelf underwater robotic vehicles using Python and C++. Together, we'll navigate the waters of this complex and rewarding field, learning from industry professionals and guest lecturers who are true experts in their domain.</p>
<p>Whether you're already passionate about robotics, interested in marine engineering, or just excited about learning something new, this course will provide you with a hands-on, immersive experience. By the end of the program, you'll be proficient in operating and controlling underwater robots, capable of planning and executing underwater missions, and well-versed in the real-world applications and challenges of underwater robotics.</p>
<p>Your journey will be both challenging and rewarding. Along the way, you'll develop not only technical skills but also critical thinking, teamwork, and problem-solving abilities. These skills will serve you well beyond the confines of this course, in whatever academic or career paths you choose to explore in the future.</p>
<p>Remember, every great journey begins with a single step. Today, you're taking that step. We encourage you to dive in headfirst, ask questions, and make the most of this unique experience. We're excited to see where this underwater adventure will take you!</p>
<p>Stay curious, stay excited, and most importantly, enjoy the journey!</p>
<p>Best,</p>
<p>Mohamed Saad Ibn Seddik, Dr.Eng.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>welcome</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>